Trent Hand Developertrent@gmail.com 931-538-5081

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly dependable Software Developer and enthusiastic team player dedicated to streamlining processes and efficiently resolving project issues. A highly desirable combination of client-facing experience with solid programming skills creates a wealth of opportunities for excellence. https://trenthand.github.io/

PROJECTS

Farm Bureau Insurance of TN Customer Service Portal

Our code base has been inherited by an overseas agency. FBITN were not pleased with the progress of the application and has asked Provisions to take over. My primary responsibilities are updating all the styling and completing functionality of the links and UI elements. This involves a heavy amount of HTML/CSS rework, along with a strong understanding of AngularJS.

Django Comic Book Store

Custom website built entirely within the Django framework using Stripe to facilitate credit card purchases. Styling is customized using CSS and JavaScript to enhance front-end functionality not readily available in Pvthon.

https://github.com/TrentHand/ComicStore

TrentSnaps

An iOS Snapchat clone storing data through Firebase. This is using CocoaPods to import features into my apps, primarily Firebase. This application mirrors the popular social networking app SnapChat. Users can take a photo, add a description, and send the photo to a friend. After the recipient views the photo and exits, the photo is deleted and no longer accessible. The sign-in is simplified: users enter an email/password. If the user already exists, they are signed in. If not, TrentSnaps will create a user for them. https://github.com/TrentHand/ComicStore

BookCollector

An iOS app built entirely from Swift. Users are able to snap a photo with their phone, add a title, and store the book locally on the device. This app was created so I could remember books I've already purchased when shopping at our local bookstore.

https://github.com/TrentHand/Swift_Book_Collector

GottaGetGit

Teaching is a passion of mine. This is a presentation I gave to a local FreeCodeCamp study group to help them understand Git/Github more fully. Slides are included in the comments to the video.

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZHL80-Ts_Vk

SKILLS SUMMARY

SwiftJavaScriptSQL

Django

Git/GitHubXcode

•

• AngularJS

PHP

Salesforce

WordPress

iQuery

Python

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Provisions Technology Solutions Software Developer Intern

2017-Present

Nashville, TN

- Front and Back-end development projects
- Projects range from AngularJS, .Net, Python, and any other language or framework required by the client.
- Currently redesigning the Customer Service Portal for Farm Bureau Insurance of Tennessee in AngularJS 1.2
- Next project will be to transition from AngularJS to Angular4 with Typescript.

Joshua Harr Shane Foundation (remote from Nashville, TN) Salesforce Administrator

2017

East Windsor, NJ

- Update contacts from various donor organizations to ensure current information
- Integrate 3rd party apps for use with other software platforms, like Eventbrite
- Design workflow processes to increase efficiency among volunteers
- Schedule campaigns for events held by JHSF
- Train other members on proper use of Salesforce
- Basic VisualForce and Apex development
- This is a volunteer position

Nashville Software School Software Developer

2016 - 2017

Nashville, TN

- Daily hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects.
- Created single page applications in JavaScript in the AngularJS framework as well as HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Materialize.
- Worked with jQuery for JavaScript libraries
- Project management/tracking with Trello and GitHub Issue Tracking
- Solution Design: white-boarding and wireframes
- Leveraged Diango for creating and editing MVC applications
- Deployed applications through Firebase, GitHub and Digital Ocean
- · Source code/version control with Git/GitHub
- Created servers and RESTful API's with Django REST framework
- Retrieved and stored database information in Firebase and SQLite and PostgreSQL
- Practiced TDD with Python's unit test framework

BLRTechnical Account Executive

2014 - 2015

Brentwood, TN

- Positioned web portal solutions designed to ensure compliance and reduce administrative task time for professionals in the Human Resources Industry.
- Salesforce experience as a user.
- 500% YTD Attainment

Sulemon Secondary School English as a Second Language Teacher

2012 - 2014

Antalya, Turkey

- Taught children ages 5-16
- Adult classes given for business professionals in the evenings
- Primarily taught through interactive engagements (songs, pop culture references, local field trips)
- Certified TESOL teacher

Dell 2010-2012 Storage and Server Specialist Nashville, TN

Positioned technical solutions for large data center deployments, involving at least \$50K/year in

- annual IT spend. Divided time between uncovering new projects, creating technical solutions, positioning the Dell solution in relation to the competition, completing the sales process with an order from the client, and
- following up to ensure the solution was performing as expected. Heavy Salesforce experience as a user at this position, including providing feedback for processes, reporting metrics, and overall usability of the implemented system.
- Consistently achieved and exceeded sales quotas with a high level of client satisfaction
- Top Ten Rep, 4 quarters, outperforming set quota and all metrics.
- #1 Sales Rep in division. 2 quarters
- 1st round pick for all advanced Sales and Technical Trainings
- 3 promotions in two years

Other Work Experience

2003 - 2010 Nashville, TN 2009 - 2010 Sprint, Inside Sales Representative Maximus Marketing, Lead Outside Sales Trainer Nashville. TN 2006 – 2009 American Income Life, Insurance Producer Nashville, TN 2005-2006 US Army Corp of Engineers, Carpentry/Masonry Specialist Bagram, Afghanistan2003-2005

TRAINING

Public Relations, Middle Tennessee State University Murfreesboro, TN — 2005